<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vidhi Mody</title>
    <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vidhi Mody</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vidhi-mody.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter Two</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-two/</guid>
      <description>“Its the not the Destination, It&amp;rsquo;s the journey.”
~ Ralph Waldo
 It&amp;rsquo;s been less than a month but this community has really grown on me. The past few weeks have been really eventful. A huge shoutout to my mentor, Željko for giving me the best on-boarding experience ever. In this short span, I got to meet the entire QTE &amp;amp; Release Engineering team. I also gained a new sense of professionalism and a clearer view of what it meant to be working as a community!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K Closest Points to Origin: Day 30 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/k-closest-points-to-origin-day-30-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/k-closest-points-to-origin-day-30-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Data dominates. If you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the right data structures and organized things well, the algorithms will almost always be self-evident. Data structures, not algorithms, are central to programming.”
~ Rob Pike
 Day 30 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: K Closest Points to Origin We have a list of points on the plane. Find the K closest points to the origin (0, 0).
(Here, the distance between two points on a plane is the Euclidean distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule: Day 29 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/course-schedule-day-29-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/course-schedule-day-29-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Data dominates. If you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the right data structures and organized things well, the algorithms will almost always be self-evident. Data structures, not algorithms, are central to programming.”
~ Rob Pike
 Day 29 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Course Schedule There are a total of numCourses courses you have to take, labeled from 0 to numCourses-1.
Some courses may have prerequisites, for example to take course 0 you have to first take course 1, which is expressed as a pair: [0,1]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting Bits: Day 28 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/counting-bits-day-28-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/counting-bits-day-28-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Premature optimization is the root of all evil.”
~ Donald Knuth
 Day 28 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Counting Bits Given a non negative integer number num. For every numbers i in the range 0 ≤ i ≤ num calculate the number of 1&amp;rsquo;s in their binary representation and return them as an array.
Sample Testcase Testcase 1
Input: 2Output: [0,1,1]Testcase 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possible Bipartition: Day 27 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/possible-bipartition-day-27-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/possible-bipartition-day-27-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Without requirements or design, programming is the art of adding bugs to an empty text file.”
~ Louis Srygley
 Day 27 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Possible Bipartition Given a set of N people (numbered 1, 2, ..., N), we would like to split everyone into two groups of any size.
Each person may dislike some other people, and they should not go into the same group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contiguous Array: Day 26 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/contiguous-array-day-26-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/contiguous-array-day-26-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“It is better to have 100 functions operate on one data structure than to have 10 functions operate on 10 data structures.”
~ Alan Perlis
 Day 26 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Contiguous Array Given a binary array, find the maximum length of a contiguous subarray with equal number of 0 and 1.
Sample Testcase Testcase 1
Input: [0,1]Output: 2Explanation: [0, 1] is the longest contiguous subarray with equal number of 0 and 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncrossed Lines: Day 25 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/uncrossed-lines-day-25-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/uncrossed-lines-day-25-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“When it comes to writing code, the number one most important skill is how to keep a tangle of features from collapsing under the weight of its own complexity.”
~ James Hague
 Day 25 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Uncrossed Lines We write the integers of A and B (in the order they are given) on two separate horizontal lines.
Now, we may draw connecting lines: a straight line connecting two numbers A[i] and B[j] such that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construct Binary Search Tree from Preorder Traversal: Day 24 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/construct-binary-search-tree-from-preorder-traversal-day-24-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/construct-binary-search-tree-from-preorder-traversal-day-24-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“One of the best programming skills you can have is knowing when to walk away for awhile.”
~ Oscar Godson
 Day 24 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Construct Binary Search Tree from Preorder Traversal Return the root node of a binary search tree that matches the given preorder traversal.
(Recall that a binary search tree is a binary tree where for every node, any descendant of node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interval List Intersections: Day 23 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/interval-list-intersections-day-23-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/interval-list-intersections-day-23-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Bad programmers worry about the code. Good programmers worry about data structures and their relationships.”
~ Linus Torvalds
 Day 23 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Interval List Intersections Given two lists of closed intervals, each list of intervals is pairwise disjoint and in sorted order.
Return the intersection of these two interval lists.
(Formally, a closed interval [a, b] (with a &amp;lt;= b) denotes the set of real numbers x with a &amp;lt;= x &amp;lt;= b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sort Characters By Frequency: Day 22 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/sort-characters-by-frequency-day-22-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/sort-characters-by-frequency-day-22-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“There are only two kinds of languages: the ones people complain about and the ones nobody uses.”
~ Bjarne Stroustrup
 Day 22 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Sort Characters By Frequency Given a string, sort it in decreasing order based on the frequency of characters.
Sample Testcase Testcase 1
Input:&amp;quot;tree&amp;quot;Output:&amp;quot;eert&amp;quot;Explanation:&#39;e&#39; appears twice while &#39;r&#39; and &#39;t&#39; both appear once.So &#39;e&#39; must appear before both &#39;r&#39; and &#39;t&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>