<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Vidhi Mody</title>
    <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Vidhi Mody</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter Four</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/gsocpedia-chapter-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/gsocpedia-chapter-four/</guid>
      <description>“With tests, we can change the behavior of our code quickly and verifiably. Without them, we really don’t know if our code is getting better or worse.”
~ Michael Feathers (Working Effectively with Legacy Code)
 One of the best experience in this duration was attending the TDD Workshop. The workshop was about learning basics of Test Driven Development - its rules and Red-Green-Refactor loop. The workshop was very interactive and all the participants worked together while writing code as well as refactoring it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter Three</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/gsocpedia-chapter-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/gsocpedia-chapter-three/</guid>
      <description>“Don’t worry if it doesn’t work right. If everything did, you’d be out of a job.”
~ Mosher’s Law of Software Engineering
 I would like to start this blog with one of the stories shared on the WaterCooler by James. (Read more about &amp;lsquo;WaterCooler&amp;rsquo; in my previous blog.)
Early in his career he worked in an aviation company in UK. The project was related to the network connectivity of the airplane during it&amp;rsquo;s entire journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edit Distance: Day 31 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/edit-distance-day-31-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/edit-distance-day-31-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“The big optimizations come from refining the high-level design, not the individual routines.”
~ Steve McConnell
 Day 31 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Edit Distance Given two words word1 and word2, find the minimum number of operations required to convert word1 to word2.
You have the following 3 operations permitted on a word:
 Insert a character Delete a character Replace a character  Sample Testcase Testcase 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter Two</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-two/</guid>
      <description>“It&amp;rsquo;s not the Destination, It&amp;rsquo;s the journey.”
~ Ralph Waldo
 It&amp;rsquo;s been less than a month but this community has really grown on me. The past few weeks have been really eventful. A huge shoutout to my mentor, Željko for giving me the best on-boarding experience ever! (📣 You can checkout his blog on GSoC here.) In this short span, I got to meet the entire QTE &amp;amp; Release Engineering team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K Closest Points to Origin: Day 30 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/k-closest-points-to-origin-day-30-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/k-closest-points-to-origin-day-30-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Data dominates. If you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the right data structures and organized things well, the algorithms will almost always be self-evident. Data structures, not algorithms, are central to programming.”
~ Rob Pike
 Day 30 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: K Closest Points to Origin We have a list of points on the plane. Find the K closest points to the origin (0, 0).
(Here, the distance between two points on a plane is the Euclidean distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule: Day 29 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/course-schedule-day-29-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/course-schedule-day-29-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Data dominates. If you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the right data structures and organized things well, the algorithms will almost always be self-evident. Data structures, not algorithms, are central to programming.”
~ Rob Pike
 Day 29 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Course Schedule There are a total of numCourses courses you have to take, labeled from 0 to numCourses-1.
Some courses may have prerequisites, for example to take course 0 you have to first take course 1, which is expressed as a pair: [0,1]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting Bits: Day 28 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/counting-bits-day-28-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/counting-bits-day-28-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Premature optimization is the root of all evil.”
~ Donald Knuth
 Day 28 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Counting Bits Given a non negative integer number num. For every numbers i in the range 0 ≤ i ≤ num calculate the number of 1&amp;rsquo;s in their binary representation and return them as an array.
Sample Testcase Testcase 1
Input: 2Output: [0,1,1]Testcase 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possible Bipartition: Day 27 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/possible-bipartition-day-27-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/possible-bipartition-day-27-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Without requirements or design, programming is the art of adding bugs to an empty text file.”
~ Louis Srygley
 Day 27 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Possible Bipartition Given a set of N people (numbered 1, 2, ..., N), we would like to split everyone into two groups of any size.
Each person may dislike some other people, and they should not go into the same group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contiguous Array: Day 26 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/contiguous-array-day-26-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/contiguous-array-day-26-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“It is better to have 100 functions operate on one data structure than to have 10 functions operate on 10 data structures.”
~ Alan Perlis
 Day 26 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Contiguous Array Given a binary array, find the maximum length of a contiguous subarray with equal number of 0 and 1.
Sample Testcase Testcase 1
Input: [0,1]Output: 2Explanation: [0, 1] is the longest contiguous subarray with equal number of 0 and 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncrossed Lines: Day 25 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/uncrossed-lines-day-25-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/uncrossed-lines-day-25-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“When it comes to writing code, the number one most important skill is how to keep a tangle of features from collapsing under the weight of its own complexity.”
~ James Hague
 Day 25 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Uncrossed Lines We write the integers of A and B (in the order they are given) on two separate horizontal lines.
Now, we may draw connecting lines: a straight line connecting two numbers A[i] and B[j] such that:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>