<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google Summer of Code on Vidhi Mody</title>
    <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/tags/google-summer-of-code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google Summer of Code on Vidhi Mody</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vidhi-mody.github.io/tags/google-summer-of-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter Three</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/gsocpedia-chapter-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/gsocpedia-chapter-three/</guid>
      <description>“Don’t worry if it doesn’t work right. If everything did, you’d be out of a job.”
~ Mosher’s Law of Software Engineering
 I would like to start this blog with one of the stories shared on the WaterCooler by James. (Read more about &amp;lsquo;WaterCooler&amp;rsquo; in my previous blog.)
Early in his career he worked in an aviation company in UK. The project was related to the network connectivity of the airplane during it&amp;rsquo;s entire journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter Two</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-two/</guid>
      <description>“It&amp;rsquo;s not the Destination, It&amp;rsquo;s the journey.”
~ Ralph Waldo
 It&amp;rsquo;s been less than a month but this community has really grown on me. The past few weeks have been really eventful. A huge shoutout to my mentor, Željko for giving me the best on-boarding experience ever! (📣 You can checkout his blog on GSoC here.) In this short span, I got to meet the entire QTE &amp;amp; Release Engineering team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter One</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-one/</guid>
      <description>“The mission of the Wikimedia Foundation is to empower and engage people around the world to collect and develop educational content under a free license or in the public domain, and to disseminate it effectively and globally.&amp;quot;
 I am pleased to share that I have been accepted into Google Summer of Code 2020 under Wikimedia Foundation!
I believe that Open source projects are a great way of developing quality products by working together with other developers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>