<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google Summer of Code on Vidhi Mody</title>
    <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/tags/google-summer-of-code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google Summer of Code on Vidhi Mody</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vidhi-mody.github.io/tags/google-summer-of-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter Five</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/07/gsocpedia-chapter-five/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/07/gsocpedia-chapter-five/</guid>
      <description>“Patience is bitter, but its fruit is sweet.”
~ Aristotle
 If you have been following my blogs you&amp;rsquo;d know I was facing serious problems with my machine. For some reason it would auto-delete any file that I&amp;rsquo;m working on! (That&amp;rsquo;s automation for you 😵) Given the current COVID situation, it was incredibly difficult to get a new machine. After being stuck for days, Voila!
 Project Status Update Meet I had one of the most eventful weeks so far, with so many things lined up one after the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: The journey so far</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/07/gsocpedia-the-journey-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/07/gsocpedia-the-journey-so-far/</guid>
      <description>“Imagine a world in which every single human being can freely share in the sum of all knowledge.”
 Foreword Google Summer of Code (GSoC) is a global program focused on introducing students to open source software development. Students work on a 3 month programming project with an open source organization during their break from university.
As a part of Google Summer of Code, student participants are paired with a mentor from the participating organizations, gaining exposure to real-world software development and techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter Four</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/gsocpedia-chapter-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/gsocpedia-chapter-four/</guid>
      <description>“With tests, we can change the behavior of our code quickly and verifiably. Without them, we really don’t know if our code is getting better or worse.”
~ Michael Feathers (Working Effectively with Legacy Code)
 One of the best experience in this duration was attending the TDD Workshop. The workshop was about learning basics of Test Driven Development - its rules and Red-Green-Refactor loop. The workshop was very interactive and all the participants worked together while writing code as well as refactoring it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter Three</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/gsocpedia-chapter-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/06/gsocpedia-chapter-three/</guid>
      <description>“Don’t worry if it doesn’t work right. If everything did, you’d be out of a job.”
~ Mosher’s Law of Software Engineering
 I would like to start this blog with one of the stories shared on the WaterCooler by James. (Read more about &amp;lsquo;WaterCooler&amp;rsquo; in my previous blog.)
Early in his career he worked in an aviation company in UK. The project was related to the network connectivity of the airplane during it&amp;rsquo;s entire journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter Two</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-two/</guid>
      <description>“It&amp;rsquo;s not the Destination, It&amp;rsquo;s the journey.”
~ Ralph Waldo
 It&amp;rsquo;s been less than a month but this community has really grown on me. The past few weeks have been really eventful. A huge shoutout to my mentor, Željko for giving me the best on-boarding experience ever! (📣 You can checkout his blog on GSoC here.) In this short span, I got to meet the entire QTE &amp;amp; Release Engineering team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoCpedia: Chapter One</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/gsocpedia-chapter-one/</guid>
      <description>“The mission of the Wikimedia Foundation is to empower and engage people around the world to collect and develop educational content under a free license or in the public domain, and to disseminate it effectively and globally.&amp;quot;
 I am pleased to share that I have been accepted into Google Summer of Code 2020 under Wikimedia Foundation!
I believe that Open source projects are a great way of developing quality products by working together with other developers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>