<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Competitive Coding on Vidhi Mody</title>
    <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/tags/competitive-coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Competitive Coding on Vidhi Mody</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vidhi-mody.github.io/tags/competitive-coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contiguous Array: Day 26 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/contiguous-array-day-26-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/contiguous-array-day-26-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“It is better to have 100 functions operate on one data structure than to have 10 functions operate on 10 data structures. ”
~ Alan Perlis
 Day 26 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Contiguous Array Given a binary array, find the maximum length of a contiguous subarray with equal number of 0 and 1.
Sample Testcase Testcase 1
Input: [0,1]Output: 2Explanation: [0, 1] is the longest contiguous subarray with equal number of 0 and 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncrossed Lines: Day 25 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/uncrossed-lines-day-25-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/uncrossed-lines-day-25-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“When it comes to writing code, the number one most important skill is how to keep a tangle of features from collapsing under the weight of its own complexity.”
~ James Hague
 Day 25 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Uncrossed Lines We write the integers of A and B (in the order they are given) on two separate horizontal lines.
Now, we may draw connecting lines: a straight line connecting two numbers A[i] and B[j] such that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construct Binary Search Tree from Preorder Traversal: Day 24 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/construct-binary-search-tree-from-preorder-traversal-day-24-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/construct-binary-search-tree-from-preorder-traversal-day-24-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“One of the best programming skills you can have is knowing when to walk away for awhile.”
~ Oscar Godson
 Day 24 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Construct Binary Search Tree from Preorder Traversal Return the root node of a binary search tree that matches the given preorder traversal.
(Recall that a binary search tree is a binary tree where for every node, any descendant of node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interval List Intersections: Day 23 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/interval-list-intersections-day-23-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/interval-list-intersections-day-23-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Bad programmers worry about the code. Good programmers worry about data structures and their relationships.”
~ Linus Torvalds
 Day 23 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Interval List Intersections Given two lists of closed intervals, each list of intervals is pairwise disjoint and in sorted order.
Return the intersection of these two interval lists.
(Formally, a closed interval [a, b] (with a &amp;lt;= b) denotes the set of real numbers x with a &amp;lt;= x &amp;lt;= b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sort Characters By Frequency: Day 22 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/sort-characters-by-frequency-day-22-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/sort-characters-by-frequency-day-22-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“There are only two kinds of languages: the ones people complain about and the ones nobody uses.”
~ Bjarne Stroustrup
 Day 22 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Sort Characters By Frequency Given a string, sort it in decreasing order based on the frequency of characters.
Sample Testcase Testcase 1
Input:&amp;quot;tree&amp;quot;Output:&amp;quot;eert&amp;quot;Explanation:&#39;e&#39; appears twice while &#39;r&#39; and &#39;t&#39; both appear once.So &#39;e&#39; must appear before both &#39;r&#39; and &#39;t&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count Square Submatrices with All Ones: Day 21 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/count-square-submatrices-with-all-ones-day-21-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/count-square-submatrices-with-all-ones-day-21-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Data dominates. If you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the right data structures and organized things well, the algorithms will almost always be self-evident. Data structures, not algorithms, are central to programming.”
~ Rob Pike
 Day 21 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Count Square Submatrices with All Ones Given a m * n matrix of ones and zeros, return how many square submatrices have all ones.
Sample Testcase Testcase 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kth Smallest Element in a BST: Day 20 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/kth-smallest-element-in-a-bst-day-20-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/kth-smallest-element-in-a-bst-day-20-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“If you can write &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; you can change the world”
~ Raghu Venkatesh
 Day 20 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Kth Smallest Element in a BST Given a binary search tree, write a function kthSmallest to find the kth smallest element in it.
 Note: You may assume k is always valid, 1 ≤ k ≤ BST&amp;rsquo;s total elements.
 Sample Testcase Testcase 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Stock Span: Day 19 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/online-stock-span-day-19-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/online-stock-span-day-19-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Programming is breaking of one big impossible task into several very small possible tasks.”
~ Jazzwant
 Day 19 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Online Stock Span Write a class StockSpanner which collects daily price quotes for some stock, and returns the span of that stock&amp;rsquo;s price for the current day.
The span of the stock&amp;rsquo;s price today is defined as the maximum number of consecutive days (starting from today and going backwards) for which the price of the stock was less than or equal to today&amp;rsquo;s price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permutation in String: Day 18 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/permutation-in-string-day-18-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/permutation-in-string-day-18-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Every programmer is an author.”
~ Sercan Leylek
 Day 18 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Permutation in String Given two strings s1 and s2, write a function to return true if s2 contains the permutation of s1. In other words, one of the first string&amp;rsquo;s permutations is the substring of the second string.
 Note:
 The input strings only contain lower case letters. The length of both given strings is in range [1, 10,000].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find All Anagrams in a String: Day 17 of the May LeetCoding Challenge</title>
      <link>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/find-all-anagrams-in-a-string-day-17-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vidhi-mody.github.io/blogs/2020/05/find-all-anagrams-in-a-string-day-17-of-the-may-leetcoding-challenge/</guid>
      <description>“Think like a fundamentalist, code like a hacker.”
~ Erik Meijer
 Day 17 of the May LeetCoding Challenge by Leetcode
Problem definition: Find All Anagrams in a String Given a string s and a non-empty string p, find all the start indices of p&amp;lsquo;s anagrams in s.
Strings consists of lowercase English letters only and the length of both strings s and p will not be larger than 20,100.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>